Lukin Maksim, Software Engineer, http://lukin.io

Feb 19, 1990, Eastern Europe, Married

Interests:

Interested in Python, GO, TypeScript, Hardware (IoT), learning new technologies, self-development.

Experience:

— Ruby on Rails developer at Mobilunity (Nov 2019 – April 2020)

Working as Senior Engineer using Ruby on Rails, consulting clients, developing new features, optimizing existing code, resolving bugs.

— Ruby on Rails developer at Aejis (2018 – Nov 2019, ~2y)

Working as Senior Engineer using Ruby (and Rails), NodeJS/React, designing API, consulting clients, monitoring, developing tools using best practices.

— Ruby/JS Engineer at Facewatch (2013 – 2018, 5y)

Facewatch is one of the UK's leading facial recognition companies. Facewatch's cloud-based facial recognition security system safeguards businesses against crime.

Joined a team of 13 members as a backend engineer. Development API using Ruby on Rails and Sinatra, 2 week iteration, scrum methodology.

Following security requirements and data consistency - have written lots of unit, integration and acceptance tests to provide high code reliability.

Writing documentation for mobile team and frontend team as well.

The team was reduced from 13 to one member (myself), extended my developer role with project management and team leading skills for more effective working with UK client and other business related members.

Continue developing application following "<u>Service Oriented Architecture</u>" approach to make applications easy to support and developing new features and integrations.

Started working on the frontend side using Backbone.JS and <u>Asynchronous Module Definitions</u>. Security Audit/PenTests.

Migrated 2TB of highly valued evidence data to amazon S3 and missed nothing.

Integrated Facial and Number plate Recognition using external API.

Integration with Metropolitan Police (London).

Open Source contributions.

Recommendations from UK chairman and CTO are located here

— iOS Engineer at jaccomo, EVENTAGRATE (2012 – 2013, 1y)

Decided to get new experience by developing iOS applications for iPad and iPhone.

Architecting iOS applications from scratch, optimizing work on iPads 1th generation.

Created and published smart-note app with ability to record voice, add notes and pictures for iOS 7.

Developing corporate applications for iPad, bluetooth messenger for conferences.

Porting from Java/Swing application to iOS application. Development of jPass application.

— Ruby on Rails developer at GAP Intelligence (2009 – 2011, 2y)

The Data Center is an online library of our entire catalog of market intelligence reports, price & promotions databases and retail circular advertisements.

Backend development using Ruby on Rails 2, analyzing uploaded market intelligence reports using Ruby tools. Architecting applications from scratch and developing in a team of 5 members.

Using jQuery on the frontend side for ajax and UI. Migration all reports to Amazon S3 for better scalability using Ruby tools and synchronize it between demo and production buckets. Writing tests and analyze risks.

— **DevOps** at **MFS-Service** (2008 – 2009, 1y)

Administration of a network of 100 workstations, delivering server reliability. Maintaining PHP web service, developing small features and fixing bugs.

Summary:

Writing clean, <u>SOLID</u> code. Tests, automated tests, CI/CD, Amazon services. Experience in development with Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, API, Redis, Sidekiq Understanding Frontend-related side, HTML/CSS, JS (TypeScript, ReactJS, Redux, Backbone.js);

DevOps basic skills (Linux, Chef/Ansible, Docker); Had experience in iOS development, NodeJS; Agile/Scrum, TDD/BDD;

Education:

Hardware Engineering faculty (Professional College of Computer Science, 2003-2006);

Contacts:

Mobile: +38 (063) 765-49-17 Email: lukin.maksim@gmail.com

Skype: lukin.maksim

Github: https://github.com/sesharim **Linkedin**: http://linkedin.com/in/sesharim